20世紀80年代初
美蘇兩國深陷在一場曠日持久的爭斗中
本劇講述了追捕中情局史上
最危險的間諜的故事
根據真實事件改編
華盛頓特區  1985年4月16日
給我找個位置
A table for lunch.
-就您一位用餐嗎  -不
- For yourself? - No.
我等人
I'm... I'm meeting someone.
-你想喝點什么嗎  先生  -不用了
- Would you like anything to drink, sir? - No.
不然要一杯吧  馬提尼伏特加  不加冰
Actually, yes. Martini Vodka straight up.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
絕密
服務生
Waiter.
埋單  麻煩了
Check! Please.
我本該在45分鐘前和你們的一名聯絡員會面
I was supposed to meet one of your attaches 45 minutes ago.
我叫奧德里奇·詹姆斯
My name is Aldrich James.
我為中情局工作
I work for the CIA.
你們會想見我的...
I think you'll want to meet with me...
在他看過這個后
after he reads this.
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：幸田實果子  feilixiaozi  二川  瀟湘月影  橫排混血  阿包
■
翻譯：MythCreator  衛老哥    時間軸：阿包  芝麻圓子  吉吉
后期：魚骨頭    校對：衛老哥  插線    總監：zhanginfo
■
叛諜
第一季
第一集
5個月后
對大部分人來說
For most of us,
早飯會吃薄烤餅
pancakes are something we eat at breakfast,
但當它們被叫做法式薄餅時
but when you call them crepes,
里面還加了點別的
then add a few other things to the crepe...
你開玩笑呢吧
You're kidding me, right?
沒人會穿成那樣去上學
Nobody wears that to your school.
大家都這么穿
Everybody wears this to school.
男孩們也穿這個嗎
The boys, too?
告訴媽媽這很正常
Tell mom this is normal.
珊蒂  有人命令我告訴你
Sandy, I've been instructed to inform you
你女兒不得體的穿著
that the obscene clothing your daughter wearing
-實際上很正常  -爸爸
- is, in fact, normal. - Dad!
我欣賞你的斗志
I appreciate the fighting spirit.
真的  現在去把衣服換了
Honest, I do. Now go change.
多謝你站在我這邊
Thanks for having my back.
我們是同一陣線
It's us against them.
你來得及嗎
You okay?
你最好快點  不然趕不上校車了
Hey, you better hurry. You'll miss the bus.
我得走了
Yeah, I got to run.
再見啦
Bye.
中情局總部
蘭利  維吉尼亞州
現在非常明確的一件事是
One thing that's become very clear
在過去幾個月中  蘇聯
about the Soviet position in the last several months
公然反對
is their outright antagonism
總統提出的"星球大戰"計劃
to the president's Star War proposal.
今天早上  蘇聯方面的威脅
The Soviet threat was there this morning
被刊登在黨報頭版上
on the front page of the Communist-Party newspaper --
"除非結束星球大戰計劃"  《真理報》稱
"Unless there is an end to the Star Wars project," said Pravda,
"否則即將展開一場新的無休止的軍備競賽"
"There will be a new and deadly spiral of the arms race."
總編輯沃特·羅杰斯在莫斯科
Our Bureau Chief in Moscow, Walter Rodgers,
就全蘇聯對談判的態度發表了
has a report on the overall Soviet attitude
一篇報告
to negotiations.
美蘇關系的解凍
The thaw in Soviet-American relations
在蘇聯人民中得到了廣泛的好評
has been enthusiastically welcomed by the Soviet people.
一年以來
For more than a year,
他們被告知美國
they've been told the United States
即將發起一場核戰爭
was on the brink of launching a nuclear war.
在與超級大國進行的裁軍談判中
With the superpowers now launching disarmament talks,
蘇聯-東歐分部
俄羅斯人民渴望他們能夠成功
the Russian people are eager for them to succeed.
格萊姆斯
Grimes.
五分鐘后去沃利的辦公室開會
Staffer, Wally's office, five minutes.
臨時抱佛腳
Last-second heebie-jeebies.
誰慌了
Who panicked?
亞姆斯  他快崩潰了
Ames. He's got his head up his ass.
你可真是慈悲心腸的典范
You are a model of compassion.
我一看到他們就打招呼來著
I call them as I see them.
這就是你有這么多朋友的原因
Which is why you have so many friends.
但你還是愛我的  對吧
Oh, but you still love me, though, right?
莫斯科時間下午六點半
Hey. 6:00 P.M. in Moscow.
你知道你的情報專員在哪兒嗎
Do you know where your Case Officer is?
和克格勃一起喝得酩酊大醉
Getting drunk with the KGB.
五分鐘后有個會
Oh, staffer in five minutes.
在奧斯丁的辦公室  我記得
Austin's office, I know.
謝謝  路易莎
Thanks, Louisa.
早上好  羅琳
Good morning, Lorraine.
昨晚傳來的情報
Nightly cable traffic.
我看看  兩個常規報告  一個夜間行動
Okay, two routine, one night action,
三個緊急文件  都是保密案件
three immediate, all restricted cases.
-對了  要開個...  -會
- Also, there's a... - Staffer.
珊蒂·格萊姆斯
這是個錯誤
It's a mistake.
他不想帶著現金過邊境
He doesn't want to take the cash across the border.
在蘇聯境內秘密交接金錢的風險太大了
Dead-dropping money inside the Soviet Union's too risky.
間諜拿到錢之后
The asset picks up the package
容易被人看到
and anyone could see him with it.
但讓他把錢帶在身上也沒好到哪去
But having him travel with the money is just as bad.
邊界線到處都是克格勃探員
There are KGB agents at every border crossing.
珊蒂  情報放置點可藏不住兩萬盧布
Sandy, 20,000 rubles is not easy to conceal in a dead-drop location.
要是他們發現他身上有錢  會殺了他的
If they find cash on him, they'll kill him.
身帶巨款的人不一定是間諜
Cash could be a sign of criminal activity,
也可能是犯罪分子
not espionage.
而且  這是向他表明即使在蘇聯境內
And anyway, this is a perfect opportunity to show him
我們也能與他取得聯系的
that we are capable of communicating with him
絕佳機會
inside the Soviet Union.
這名間諜代號為巨錨
The asset code named GT Weigh
是一名克格勃高層探員
is a highly placed KGB officer.
他曾是我們在七十年代最早的一批間諜
He was a primary asset for us in the '70s.
他給我們提供了許多海外行動的珍貴情報
He gave us invaluable intel on overseas operations.
十周前他重新露面時
When he resurfaced 10 weeks ago,
我們答應他會多付錢
we promised him more money,
我們得好好履行這個承諾
and we need to make good on that promise.
不只這樣  我們得向他  向我們自己
But more than that, we need to prove to him --
證明我們有能力在克格勃的眼皮底下
To ourselves -- that we can run a viable operation inside KGB territory
展開行動
right under their noses.
那為什么要用如此寶貴的間諜來證明
Okay. Why prove it with such a valuable asset?
如果這只是嘗試  我們換個小人物
If this is a test case, let's use a small fry.
這不是嘗試  里克
This isn't a test case, Rick!
我們一向這么做  這是我們的行事手段
It's how we do business. It's what we do.
亞特
Art.
別問我  沃利
Don't look at me, Wally.
拿高工資的人是你
It's why they pay you the big bucks.
把錢放到放置點
Drop the money.
告訴莫斯科分站往下行動
Tell Moscow to move forward.
有信息及時匯報
And keep me updated.
保密通信
Restricted access.
莫斯科方面立即行動
Immediate action traffic, Moscow station.
按已探討方案放置巨錨資金
Proceed with GT Weigh funds dead drop as discussed.
及時匯報
Update ASAP.
美國領事館
莫斯科
"繼續巨錨行動"
"Proceed with GT Weigh."
"放置資金"
"Funds drop."
"如前所定"
"As discussed."
就這么多  站長
Here we go, chief.
希望他們清楚自己在做什么
Just hope they know what they're doing.
我希望我們都清楚自己在做什么
I hope we all know what we're doing.
你徒步過去  混進去
You move with foot traffic and you blend in,
-特別是在酒吧周圍  -好的
- Especially around bars. - Understood.
每個街角原路返回一次
Double back on every other street corner,
-至少走上兩個小時  -明白
- two hours' worth at the very least. - Got it.
注意周圍的人  比如車里的人
And look for casuals -- men in parked cars,
在你前后改變方向的行人
pedestrians who change direction ahead or behind you.
只有在確保安全時才能行動
You drop only when you are positive you are black.
絕對的安全
Absolutely positive.
杰克  我不是第一次行動了
Jack, I've done this before.
安全歸來
You be safe.
莫斯科分站有消息嗎
Traffic from Moscow station?
剛才真是抱歉
Sorry about earlier.
我只是  你知道
I just -- you know, I...
我只是不同意
I didn't agree.
你可以持有自己的觀點  里克
You're entitled to your opinion, Rick,
即使是錯誤的觀點
Even if it's wrong.
要去抽根煙嗎
Go for a smoke?
我正在戒煙
Trying to quit.
那是好事
Good for you.
但愿如此
I wish.
有情況要通知我
Let me know how it goes, huh?
格萊姆斯
Grimes.
還沒消息
Nothing yet.
-有情況就通知我  -好  第一個通知你
- Keep me informed. - Yeah, first to know.
好的
All right.
我手快被你們扭斷了
You're breaking my arm!
告訴我最新情況
Get me up to speed.
我們正在跟巨錨做資金傳遞
We were proceeding with the dead drop for GT Weigh.
廖內德·波列修克  克格勃官員
KGB officer Leonid Poleshchuk.
只說暗號
Encrypted names only.
至少他還是個人
Oh, for crying out loud, he's a human being.
亞瑟  守點規矩
Arthur. Follow protocol.
巨錨的行動地點是在彼得羅夫斯基公園
For GT Weigh in our operational location in Petrovsky park.
我們的情報專員開始行動的時間是
Our case officer started the operation at...
格林威治時間  14點20分
14:20, GMT.
之前我被告知他有兩個小時
I was told he had two hours
-來避開偵查掩護自己  -結果呢
- to evade detection and go black. - And then?
他沒能向站長復命
He never reported back to his station chief.
第一個聯系我們的是誰
Who was first contact to us?
情報專員的妻子上報了他沒回家
The case officer's wife reported that he hadn't returned home.
那是什么時候
What time was that?
格林威治時間  18點30分
18:30, GMT.
他花了兩個小時偽裝掩護
So he took two hours to go black,
把錢放進情報點  然后被抓
filled the drop, was arrested,
然后他妻子等了足足兩個小時才聯系我們
and his wife took an extra two hours grace time and called us.
面對事實吧  大伙
We need to face facts here, people --
他們包抄了我們的情報專員
They rolled up our case officer.
很可能他們知道他為什么會在那
They probably know why he was there.
這意味著
Which means...
巨錨招供了
GT weigh's been compromised.
早和你說了  這主意糟糕透頂
Told you. This was a really bad idea.
里克  現在不是怪罪別人的時候
Rick, not the moment for blame.
線報員是否已招供  只是我們單方面的猜測
Whether our asset has been compromised is a guess on our part.
可這猜測相當有說服力  華萊士
Seems like an educated guess, Wallace.
先集中注意力在已有的確定情報上吧
Let's just focus on what we know for sure.
情報專員現在在哪
Where's our case officer now?
我們認為他被關押在盧比揚卡監獄
We believe he's being held in Lubyanka prison.
通知國務院
Notify the State Department.
知會美國駐俄大使
Wake up the U.S. ambassador.
盧比揚卡監獄
蘇聯
放開我  我是一名美國外交官
Get your hands off me! I am an American diplomat!
任職于美國大使館
I work -- I work at the U.S. embassy!
我是美國的外交官
I am an American diplomat!
任職于美國大使館
I work at the U.S. embassy.
20,000盧布
20,000 rubles.
真是好大一筆錢
That's a lot of money.
我是一名美國外交官
I'm an American diplomat
任職于美國大使館
working at the U.S. embassy.
我在此要求通知美國大使
I hereby request that you call the U.S. ambassador
并告知他我受到非法拘禁
and alert him to this illegal detention.
好啊
Yes.
那我們來說說什么是合法
Let's talk of legality.
你一個美國公民
You are American citizen
卻在莫斯科市中心的
leaving 20,000 rubles
一處水泥缺口里
in piece of broken concrete...
塞了兩萬盧布
in downtown Moscow.
即使翻遍所有蘇聯法
By any reading of Soviet Law,
都會被指認為犯罪活動預謀
that speaks to impending criminal activity.
介意解釋一下嗎
You care to explain?
我是一名美國外交官
I'm an American diplomat,
任職于美國大使館
working at the U.S. embassy.
或許是為了一個女人
Perhaps it was for a woman.
你有沒有愛上過
Have you fallen in love
某位俄羅斯美人呢
with one of our Russian beauties?
情婦呢
Hmm? A mistress? Hmm?
她希望你能來照顧她
She wants you to take care of her.
這可是個...
That would be...
聽上去挺可信的故事
plausible cover story.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
或者我們彼此敞開天窗說亮話吧
Or shall we just be honest with each other? Huh?!
你不是什么美國外交官
You are no more American diplomat
而我也不是拉達工廠的工人
than I am comrade worker in Lada factory!
我們都是間諜
We are both spies!
而你被我逮了個現行
And I caught you spying!
你知道
You know...
想要擺脫目前的處境  回到你家人身邊
all you really have to do to make this all better,
你真正要做的
to be released to your family,
是指認我們逮捕的那個男人是你的間諜
is confirm that the man we arrested was your asset.
有話直說  格萊姆斯
Hey. Spit it out, Grimes.
我們的情報專員正在蹲大牢呢
Our case officer's sitting in a prison cell right now.
天知道克格勃會怎么拷問他
God only knows how the KGB is interrogating him.
我會打電話給國務院  讓他們提出抗議
I'll call the State Department, they'll scream and yell,
把他從牢里弄出來
and we'll get him out of there.
但你真正擔心的不是這個  是不是
But that's not what you're really worried about, is it?
那個間諜  波列修克
The asset -- Poleshchuk.
我和他一起在巴拿馬待過一個月
I spent a month with him in Panama.
他粗魯不堪  整日酗酒
Wild man, drank like a fish.
但我漸漸開始喜歡他
But I grew to like him.
他給我講過一個故事
He told me this story,
說他想要用一瓶威士忌
said he wanted to bribe a potential recruit
收買一名潛在間諜
with a bottle of whiskey,
但他的克格勃上司拒絕付賬
but his KGB boss wouldn't pay for it.
他對此耿耿于懷
That stuck in his craw so bad,
第二天  他自愿加入了中情局
the next day, he volunteered for the CIA.
他可能是我們唯一一個
He's probably the only spy we ever got
只用一瓶酒就買通了的間諜
for a single bottle of booze.
我可能說錯了
Well... I could be wrong.
但我們無法確定他是否已經招供
We can't be sure he's been compromised.
波列修克有老婆和孩子
Poleshchuk has a wife and children.
他知道他在做什么
He knew what he was getting into.
是嗎  你確定嗎
Did he? Are you so sure?
他們會把他拖到冒牌法官面前
They'll haul him in front of a phony judge,
進行模擬審訊
they'll stage a mock trial,
進行宣判  判他有罪  然后...
pronounce him guilty, sentence him, and then --
他們會把他拖到院子里
They'll drag him out into a courtyard
執行槍決
and put a bullet in the back of his head.
珊蒂
Sandy...
這不是你的錯
It's not your fault.
是我堅持要他把錢藏在蘇聯境內
I pushed to have him dead-drop the money inside the USSR.
如果不是我  也許他現在已經自由
If I hadn't, maybe he'd be free now,
正和他的家人團聚
home with his family.
你做的是對的
It was the right thing to do.
但事情搞砸了
But it blew up on us!
目前為止我們還不知道為什么
And we have no idea why yet.
格萊姆斯  繼續你的工作
Grimes, you stay on task.
你得努力工作
You keep your nose to the grindstone,
但最重要的是  你要把生活中的一切分開
but mostly you keep everything in your life separate --
工作  家庭  間諜
Work, family, assets.
你必須把它們分開
You have got to compartmentalize.
我不知道我能不能做到
I don't know if I can do that.
我不知道我是不是那樣的人
I don't know if I'm that person.
如果你做不到
Well... If you can't,
這份工作會毀了你的
this job will tear you apart.
整個克格勃大樓里  只有一個地方
There is only one place to have a private conversation
能進行秘密談話
in entire KGB building.
巴拿馬
你知道在哪嗎
And do you know where that is?
男廁所
沒錯  廁所是我們完成本職工作的地方
在酒吧里大聲談及你雇主的名字
Broadcasting the name of your employer in a bar
可不是個明智的舉動
might not be the smartest move.
也許我們應該換個地方接著談
Maybe we should take this conversation someplace else.
你和我  我們會是最佳間諜組合
You and I, we could be the best spy team.
就我們倆  去巴黎或是塔西提島
Just the two of us -- Paris or maybe Tahiti.
我不這么想
I don't think so.
如果我不嘗試一下
I would be haunted forever...
我會一輩子心里不安的
if I didn't at least try.
美國大使館
莫斯科
他是我們使館的工作人員
He's part of my diplomatic staff
依照國際法  擁有豁免權
and, by international law, has immunity.
貴方觸犯了蘇維埃社會主義共和聯盟的法律
You have violated the laws and integrity
威脅到我國領土完整
of the Union of Soviet Socialist --
我方絕對尊重
We have absolute respect
蘇聯的領土完整
for the territorial integrity of the Soviet Union.
并竭盡全力遵守貴國的法律
We make every attempt to abide by your sovereign laws.
你在說謊
You are lying.
我們知道貴國在我國進行間諜活動
We know you run spies in my country.
這一行為是對蘇聯的嚴重侮辱
This is a terrible insult to the Soviet Union.
我們絕不會把間諜安插在貴國主權范圍...
We would not employ a spy within the sovereign borders of --
那兩萬盧布顯然是用來
20,000 rubles was obviously...
-這不是問題的關鍵  -通過行賄
- That is not the issue here. - A bribe...
以策反我國公民賣國通敵
to get our citizens to betray their country.
如果別無選擇的話  我會尋求白宮介入的
If I have to get the white house involved, I will.
他掛電話了  長官
I believe he hung up, sir.
盧比揚卡監獄  蘇聯
對你的拘留到此為止了
You are being released from detention.
不過對你的指控依舊成立
The charges against you still stand.
從此刻起
From this moment,
你已經被我蘇聯列為不受歡迎者
you are persona non grata in Soviet Union.
限你兩個小時之內收拾個人物品
You have two hours to collect your belongings
離開我國
and leave the country.
一份就此事件的通知已經發往你們的大使館
A letter to this effect has been sent to your embassy.
他就在這  是不是
He's here, isn't he?
就在這棟樓里
In the building.
被關在另一間牢房
In another cell.
我們俄國人對盧比揚卡監獄流傳著一種說法
Russians have saying about Lubyanka prison.
說這是莫斯科最高的建筑
They call it the tallest building in Moscow.
知道為什么嗎
You know why?
因為從地下室
Because, from the basement,
你就可以一眼望到西伯利亞
you can see all the way to Siberia.
我們的情報專員已被從盧比揚卡監獄釋放
Our case officer has been released from Lubyanka.
他有兩個小時離開俄國
He has two hours to leave the country.
俄國佬正在把他押上飛機
They're putting him on a plane right now.
好的  謝謝
All right. Thank you.
算是避免了一場危機
One crisis averted.
我會給所有站長拍份電報
I'll write to all station chiefs.
告訴他們之前是你負責巨錨
You handled GT Weigh in the past.
并警告有一定可能
Let them know there's a possibility
-他是被出賣的  -好的
- He's been compromised. - Good.
珊蒂還有
And, Sandy...
巨錨
叫他們再次核查各站的行動
Ask them to double check their operations.
任何有機密權限的職員
Employees with access,
通信  情報手段
Communications, tradecraft --
任何方面只要是出一點差錯
Compromise could have come from anywhere --
都可能導致機要信息泄露
a tiny mistake from any of them.
告訴他們  眼睛放尖點
You tell them to look hard.
奧斯丁說你們有撥往莫斯科分站的
Austin said you had an immediate-action cable
應急聯絡專線
to go to Como?
是的
Uh, yeah.
你認識他
You knew him.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我們還不確定他已經犧牲了
We don't know that he's been lost.
也對  是我的錯
You're right. My mistake.
這趟玩的還盡興嗎  伙計
希望你能滿意
因為你的死期已經到了
你一個蘇聯人
還是個克格勃特工
曾經宣誓效忠國家
卻選擇背叛祖國當美國佬的走狗
到底為什么  廖內德
就為了幾盧布  一雙好鞋
我的兒子生病了   我必須回家
不過  至少他還活著 是吧
我的克格勃上司謝里瓦斯托夫專橫殘暴
所以你就置國家的安危于不顧
我父親去世的時候
連自己的葬禮都不允許我參加
我被激怒了
這是一個兒子對父親的愛
你能明白嗎
這總能算得上原因了吧
算個屁
我全是照著你們要求的去做的
I did everything you told me to do.
我花了兩個小時反跟蹤
I took two hours going black.
在到公園之前總算是甩干凈了
I was alone well before I got to the park.
有沒有可能你把尾隨者漏掉了
Is there any chance you missed your tail?
不可能
I don't think so.
所有反跟蹤的過程都無懈可擊
No, the tradecraft was good.
在你離開大使館的時候
Did anything strike you as different,
有沒有遇到什么不尋常的事情
out of the ordinary when you left the embassy?
他們每天都跟著我出大使館
They follow me out of that embassy every single day.
每天都是相同的情形
Every day, it's always the same.
昨晚也是如此
It was the same last night.
克格勃  他們毫不松懈
The KGB -- they're relentless.
在公園有什么發現  在你被捕之前
What about at the park, before the arrest?
有什么  奇怪的事物或者...
Was there anything, you know, strange or...?
我看見一個人
I saw someone.
我覺得可能是諜報員
I thought it might have been the asset.
他朝我揮了揮手  不過后來...
He waved, but then...
一切發生得太快了
It all happened so fast.
我們休息十分鐘
Let's take a 10-minute break.
還有一件事
One more thing.
在盧比揚卡審訊我的審訊員
My interrogator at Lubyanka
一直要我供出諜報員的名字
kept asking me to confirm the name of the asset
我沒說  但是...
I was dropping for, but...
我覺得他已經知道了
I think he already knew.
如果公園里的那個人是諜報員
If the man in the park was the asset,
他為什么到情報傳遞點來
why would he come to the dead drop?
情報傳遞點的關鍵目的就是
The whole point of a dead drop
保證你與你的情報專員
is you aren't in the same place
永遠不會出現在同一地點
as your case officer, ever.
或許他怕他已經被懷疑上
Maybe he was afraid he was under suspicion.
他揮手是在警告我們的情報專員離開傳遞點
He waved to warn our case officer off the drop.
-珊蒂  -如果是那樣的話
- Sandy. - If that's the case,
克格勃無法確定巨錨是間諜
the KGB wouldn't be sure GT Weigh was a spy.
他們需要更多的證據
They'll need more proof.
珊蒂  珊蒂...
Sandy, Sandy...
半小時前收到的...
This came in half an hour ago...
從盧比揚卡內部一個低級線人處得到的消息
From a low-level in-place source at Lubyanka.
波列修克昨天被處決了
Poleshchuk was executed yesterday.
我們明早要做的第一件事
We're gonna need a report to take to the Seventh Floor
就是把報告送去局長辦公室
first thing tomorrow morning.
里根總統今天說
President Reagan said today
在日內瓦峰會上所取得的一項重大成果
that the great measure of success at the Geneva Summit
就是與米哈伊爾·戈爾巴喬夫
was his one-on-one conversations alone
所進行的一對一談話
with Mikhail Gorbachev.
蘇聯通過多種方式試圖
The Soviets tried in a couple of ways
阻止美國的太空導彈防御計劃
to stop the American program for a missile defense in space.
媽媽  你去哪兒了
Mom, where have you been?
我得跟你說一下星期六晚上的事
I need to talk to you about Saturday night,
本吉·帕拉爾想帶我去參加聚會  還有...
because Benji Parrell wants to take me to this party, and --
一邊玩去
Not now!
這很傷人
That was bad.
我去道歉
I'll go apologize.
談談嗎
Talk?
你知道我不能說
You know I can't.
她從不在我身邊
She's never around.
她在的時候總又那么討人厭
And when she is, she's so obnoxious.
我真受不了待在她身邊
I can't stand to be around her.
是的
Yeah.
-準備好了嗎  -我想是吧
- You ready? - I think so.
簡短明了  切入主題
Keep it short and to the point.
亞特  珊蒂
Art. Sandy...
感謝你們前來
Thanks for coming.
局長你認識的
You know the director.
很高興再次見到你  長官
It's good to see you again, sir.
長官  正如你所知
Sir, as you probably know,
我們與巨錨的情報投送
Our dead drop to GT Weigh
兩天前在莫斯科被截擊了
was intercepted two days ago in Moscow.
我們的情報專員被捕
Our case officer was arrested,
我們有理由相信我們的諜報員被出賣了
and we had reason to believe our asset had been compromised.
昨晚  我們得到可靠消息
Last night, we learned with certainty
巨錨在盧比揚卡監獄被處決了
that GT Weigh had been executed in Lubyanka prison.
我們正在對此事件展開調查
We're now beginning the process of investigating the nature --
打斷一下  珊蒂
Let me stop you there, Sandy.
我找借口把你叫來
I brought you here under slightly false pretenses.
我覺得中情局局長
While I do want the D.C.I.
想要聽到的是這次行動的細節
to hear the details of the operation,
更重要的是
more importantly,
我有想要告訴你的事情
I wanted to fill you all in on something else.
巨錨的犧牲只是冰山一角
The compromise of GT Weigh is just the tip of the iceberg.
情況比你想象的嚴重得多
The situation is far worse than you can possibly imagine.
在過去的三個月里  我們損失了
We've lost more assets in the last three months
比史上任何時候都要多的諜報員
than at practically any other time in our history.
巨濤是一個極其成功的竊聽器
Gt Taw was an extremely successful tap
它被安裝在一條位于莫斯科市中心地下的
we'd been running on a KGB phone line underground
克格勃電話線路上
in central Moscow.
這一機密保密級別很高
It was a highly restricted case.
只有極少數人知道它的存在
Very few people knew about it.
線路很難接入
The line was difficult to access,
但我們從那條線路得到的信息是無價的
but the intel we gained on it was invaluable --
行動的詳細計劃  涉及官員姓名
operational detail, officer names,
地址  還有克格勃的戰略情報
locations, KGB strategic intelligence.
三個月之前
Three months ago,
當一名特工人員從監聽線路上取回錄音帶時
while an officer was retrieving tapes from a tapped line,
警報被觸發了
an alarm sounded.
我們安裝報警裝置是為了提醒情報專員
We had set up the alarm to warn case officers
一旦監聽線路被人發現
in case the tap had become compromised,
結果果不其然
which it had.
但那只是開始
That was just the beginning.
上個月
Last month,
我們在慕尼黑工作了很長時間的間諜
a longtime asset for us in Munich
收到克格勃讓其返回莫斯科的指令
was recalled by the KGB to Moscow.
他們說他成年的兒子有健康問題
They told him his grown son had a health issue
需要他立刻回家
which needed his immediate attention back home.
當這名特工給在蘇聯的朋友打電話時
When the asset called family friends in the Soviet Union
才確定他兒子生病的事是假的
and established that the story about his son was false,
我們建議他立即撤離
we recommended he be exfiltrated immediately.
克格勃追他追的很緊
The KGB came after him, hard.
我們很幸運
We got lucky,
那名間諜毫發無傷的逃走了
and the asset escaped unharmed.
他現在身處美國本土的一間安全屋
He's currently in a safe house inside the U.S.
但巨錨就沒那么幸運了
But GT Weigh, obviously, is not.
如果不是克格勃走了狗屎運
Either the KGB has gotten extremely lucky of late
那就一定是我們有了大麻煩了
or we have a serious problem on our hands.
無論如何  我們遭受了重創
Whatever it is, we are getting hammered,
我們在蘇聯布置的情報網絡正在遭受破壞
destroying our eyes and ears inside the Soviet Union.
更不用說殺人的那些事
Not to mention killing people.
這件事要盡可能先壓在局里
This needs to stay in the building as long as possible.
總統并不知情
The president doesn't know.
媒體當然更不可能知道
The press certainly cannot know.
我們必須盡快把這事查清
We need to figure this out fast.
你們在東蘇分部的人馬
Your team in S.E. Division
必須在我們徹底失去情報來源
needs to get their heads back in the game
并輸掉這該死的冷戰之前
before we go completely blind
重整旗鼓
and lose the damn cold war.
無論什么困難  你都能擊敗它
Whatever it is, you will beat it.
你是我遇到過的最聰明  最堅強
You're the smartest, the toughest,
最英勇的女人
The most heroic woman I've ever met.
那沒問題嗎
And is that okay?
我的意思是  你真的想要那么堅強
I mean, do you want a wife who can be that tough,
把生活分割出去的妻子嗎
Who compartmentalizes her life?
家庭在一邊  工作在另一邊
Family here, work there?
而且對她最愛的那個人隱瞞很多秘密
Who keeps secrets from the one person she loves most?
我們每個人都有秘密  桑迪
We all keep secrets, Sandy.
想象一下如果我們了解凱莉
Imagine how much we'd worry
生活中發生的每一件事
if we knew every single thing about Kelly's life...
知道她說的每一句話  該有多擔心
...if we knew every word she said.
有些時候秘密能讓人遠離傷害
Sometimes a secret keeps the hurt away.
你知道  我娶你
You know, I married you...
是因為我清楚地知道你要去拯救世界
because it was clear to me you were out to save the world.
無論付出什么代價  你都會做到
Whatever it took, you would make that happen,
當你真的做到時  我會為你而驕傲
and that I would be proud of you when you did.
這個家的每一個人
Everyone in this family
都知道你為什么要擔起這份責任
knows why you do what you do.
但你自己知道嗎
But do you know why you do it?
因為你是個勇士
Because you are a warrior.
為了保護你的祖國
Protecting your country.
為了我們
You do it for us.
守護我們的安全
To keep us safe.
我要回去工作了
I have to go back to the office.
我不等你睡了
I won't be waiting up.
公園里揮手的那個人
The man in the park who waved.
你整晚都在這里嗎
You been here all night?
他不是為了警告我們的情報專員離開
He wasn't trying to warn our case officer off the drop.
他是要確保情報專員看到他
He was making sure our case officer saw him,
注意到他
noticed him.
你一直沒睡過覺  對嗎
You didn't get any sleep, did you?
諜報員揮手的時候
The asset was here
就站在這里
When he waved.
情報專員說
The case officer said
克格勃從這棟樓出現
that the KGB came from around this building.
你看看這公園的地形
Well, look at the geography of the park.
諜報員是可以看到他們的
The asset would have seen them.
他應該知道克格勃官員就在那里
He would've known the KGB officers were there,
埋伏  蹲守  也就是說
hiding, waiting, which means...
他不是那個諜報員
He wasn't the asset.
他在裝樣子  是個替身
He was a plant, a double.
也就是說
Which means...
整件事都是陷阱
The whole thing was a setup.
克格勃就是要確保
The KGB wanted to make sure
我們得到的情報是說
that it got reported back to us
那個諜報員被跟蹤并且在公園被逮捕
that the asset was followed and arrested in the park --
這樣看起來好像他們剛剛知道
to make it look like they just figured out
波列修克是個間諜
that Poleshchuk was a spy.
也許他們已經懷疑  對他進行了監控
Maybe that they had suspicions, had him under surveillance,
但他們已經知道
but they knew,
而且已經知道有一陣子了
and they must have known for a while.
我甚至敢打賭
I'd put even money
波列修克在被他們處決之前
that Poleshchuk had been sitting in a jail
已經在監獄里待了一個月
for a month when they executed him.
公園里整個行動只是為了迷惑我們
The whole operation in the park is meant to confuse us.
純粹是演戲
Pure theater.
如果他們這么大費周章  那只可能是
And they'd only put on a play if --
他們在掩蓋更重要的事情
If they were covering up something more important --
非常非常重要
a lot more important.
克格勃在掩蓋真正的問題
KGB's hiding the true problem.
他們能得到局里的情報  亞特
They have an in to the agency, Art.
他們打入我們內部了
They've cracked us.
回家  睡個覺  這是命令
Go home, get some sleep. That's an order.
還有  格萊姆斯
Oh, and, Grimes --
明天見
See you tomorrow.
一大早要不要來一根提提神
Want to grab an early smoke?
不  我戒了  再不抽了
No. I quit -- for good.
你要走了嗎
You're leaving?
是的  來半天了
Yeah. Been here a while.
告訴我  巨錨的問題解決了嗎
Tell me -- solve GT Weigh?
還沒有
Not yet.
但我們會解決的
But we'll get there.
再見  里克
See you, Rick.
再見
See ya.
絕密
不吃完營養早餐誰也不許出家門
Nobody leaves this house without a nutritious breakfast.
廣告里怎么說的來著
What do they say in the commercials?
一天中最重要的一頓飯
The most important meal of the day.
這一身是去學校的行頭嗎
Now, that's a school outfit.
這是睡衣  媽媽
These are pajamas, mom.
而且是很得體的睡衣
Yeah, well, they're appropriate pajamas.
我很喜歡  加里
I like them. Gary?
我也喜歡  男孩子們也會喜歡的
Love them. Boys will, too.
沒吃夠的話自己再拿
Help yourself if you want any more.
好豐盛啊
A feast.
楓糖漿
Maple syrup.
他們有人打入了我們內部
They got an in to our setup.
我們得一層層撥開疑云找到他
We just got to peel back the layers and find it.
這是你的看法嗎
Your concept?
不  團隊一起得出的結論
No, a group came up with it.
主要是格萊姆斯
Grimes, mostly.
好吧
All right.
那我們就開始行動
Let's get to work, then.
亡羊補牢
Stop the bleeding.
鬼知道接下來他們會給我們用什么損招
God only knows what they'll throw at us next.
羅馬
對  我叫維塔利·尤琴科
Yes, my name is Vitaly Yurchenko.
我正在大使館前面的電話亭里
I am phoning you from the telephone box
給你打電話
in front of the embassy.
我是克格勃負責反間諜的資深上校
I am senior counterintelligence colonel in the KGB...
我想要投誠
and I wish to defect.